Owen Edwards

Profile

Dedicated and passionate problem solver who excels when working under pressure, I am seeking new opportunities in Web Development. I am searching for new challenges in a fast paced environment. I am open to relocation, remote work, and new technology stacks.

After completing my college course with 33 distinctions, I began an English and Classics BA at Nottingham University. However, after two years I decided that I wanted to turn my interest in programming into a career. Since then I have been studying programming and web development full time.

Employment History

Photographers Assistant, Oakfield Photography, Newport

JANUARY 2017 - JANUARY 2019

Duties involved attending events with the lead photographer, maintaining all equipment, and managing the appointment book. The role also involved a great deal of customer management, ensuring that every need was met and answering any questions clients might have.

I handled sensitive client information in a confidential and respectful manner, and often wrote, edited, and distributed communication materials. Alongside my regular duties I also designed and built the company website (oakfield-photography.com). The site was built with JavaScript and CSS, and I used a NodeJS server connected to the Cloudinary API for image gallery management.

Shop Assistant, The Locked Horns, Chepstow

JANUARY 2014 - JANUARY 2016

Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee in a customer facing role. The position involved maintaining a friendly and welcoming attitude, while also having a good working knowledge of the shop's current stock in order to manage inventory and new purchases.

Education

8 GCSEs, Chepstow Comprehensive

SEPTEMBER 2002 - MAY 2007

IT(B), English Language(B), English Literature(B), History(B), Art(A), Maths(C), Science(B), Additional Science(C).

Humanities, Coleg Gwent, Newport

SEPTEMBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016

33 Distinctions.

University of Nottingham, Nottingham

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2019

Courses

Harvard CS50

The Complete Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy

Details

07392540684 owenhedwards@gmail.com

Links

<u>Portfolio -</u> <u>www.owenedwards.me</u>

Skills

JavaScript

C#

HTML

CSS, SASS

React, Redux

NodeJS

PostgreSQL

Bootstrap 4

C

Git

Hobbies

In my free time I love to create small programs and apps to solve problems for myself and friends; an example of which would be my Community NPC Generator project.

Designed to make running table-top roleplaying games easier, it streamlines the process of randomly generating characters. It was made with React, CSS and NodeJS. A unique feature is the ability for users to login and submit character generation names/images/characteristics for others to generate and use.

I also love reading science fiction, classical history, and listening to the Grim Fandango soundtrack on repeat.